CV of Louis Kapend

Web developer

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Enthusiastic, reliable and friendly individual who works hard to achieve and surpass set goals. Adaptable, committed and organized with a lot of problem-solving experience. Good communication skills and ability to speak many languages (English, French and Swahili). A quick learner, who always seeks learning opportunities, works well in a team as well as individually.

Innovative, task-driven, proficiency in writing clean codes and implementation of new features according to users' feedback.

Personal Details Names:

Surname: Kapend

Gender: Male

Date of Birth: 03 July 1983

Louis

Marital Status: Married

Cellphone: 067 163 0558

Email: louiskapend2016@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/louis-diur-kapend-732033240/

GitHub: https://github.com/Lint2016

Languages: English, French and Swahili

Nationality: Congolese with SA valid permit

EDUCATION INFORMATION

Secondary Education

High School: Imara High School (DRCongo)

Grade Passed: Grade 12

Subjects: Mathematical, English, Biology, French, Physics, History and

Chemistry.

Year Completed 1995 -2002

Higher Education

Institute IIE Varsity Sandton College

Introduction to personal computing

Year Completed 2012

COMPUTER SKILLS

MS Word: 10+ Years' experience. **MS Excel**: 10+ Years' experience.

HTML 5: 2 Years 'experience. CSS: 2 Years 'experience. Bootstrap: 2 Years 'experience.

JavaScript: 2 Years 'experience. JQuery: 2 Years 'experience. MS Outlook: 10+ Years 'experience.

WordPress: 1 Year experience. SEO: 1Year experience. Node JS: 1 Year experience

Git, GitHub: 2 Years experience. Command Line: 2 years experience. React.js: 1 Year experience

PHP: 2 Years experience. SQL: 2 Years experience. Express JS: 1 Year experience

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

1.Company Tirhisano insurance brokers

Position held Call Centre Agent

Employment Period February 2010 - December 2012

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Handling phone calls, emails then assist with implementation, monitoring, and reporting of the service delivery of the allocated service desk team.
- Closing new business deals via cold calls and face to face marketing.
- Retention of old and new clients, following up on the best company procedure to maintain a healthy business relationship with them.
- Updating the sales team on new products (Reservations, promotions...)
- Support operational management in the delivery on the service desk operational objectives SLAs related to the allocated team. Assist with the management compliments and complaints.

2.Company Hotel Express

Position held Customer service agent

Employment Period February 2013 - March 2016

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Making outbound calls to existing and prospect customers advising them on new products or packages.
- Planning the marketing strategies to acquire new clients, and grow the company revenue.
- Training of newbies on how to talk to clients and close deals on the phone, and face to face if need be.

- Managing accounts, especially for French speaking clients, for better communication.
- Cold calling and closing deals with potential clients, from the leads provided through the lead generator department.
- Retention of clients and ensuring that a good and healthy relationship is maintained throughout the existence of the contract.
- Provision of support and accurate information to customers and end users via the telephone, assisting the customer to understand how to use the product properly and logging and resolving problems through the following of policies and procedures for call handling and client problems solving.
- Ensuring that all communication with customers is within the guidelines of the client. Ensures that all data is collected accurately and follows up on calls, chats and keeping records of calls placed and deal appropriately with relevant client escalations

3.Company Pick and Pay LMDC (Longmeadow distribution Centre)

Position held Data Processor

Employment Period June 2016 - May 2022

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Processing information received through SAP system while making sure that orders are shipped accordingly.
- Handling incoming calls, emails, and social media queries.
- Reporting to my supervisor and logistics team all suspicious transactions.
- -Creation of clients list of orders and email templating for marketing purpose using Html and CSS.
- -Drafting quotations, Proforma invoices and admin duties.

4.Company COMM (call on me marketing)

Position held Lead generator (freelance)

Employment Period April 2023 – August 2023

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Providing leads for Discovery Financial Advisors.

- Setting up appointments between potential clients and Discovery Financial Advisors to discuss their Long-Term Portfolio.

5.Company Nevy's Language (Language school in Canada)

Position held Student Recruiter & enrolment representative(freelance)

Employment Period March 2023 – June 2023

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Organizing and managing leads into the company CRM system.
- Calling the leads, understanding the customer's language needs and presenting our program.
- Selling the lead our program and helping them pay and register into our system.
- Conducting a language assessment to help them figure out at which English Level they are.

REFERENCES

* Pick and Pay LMDC (Longmeadow distribution Centre)

Mr. Khoza

Position: Line Manager

Tel: 060 8961 018

* HOTEL EXPRESS

Mr. Alain Mpata

Position: Team Leads Tel: 079 05 30 113

*COMM

Mrs. Masoodah Snyders

Position: Training facilitator

Tel: 010 140 5721

*NEVY'S LANGUAGE

Mrs. Marie Josee Excels

Position: Sales Manager

Email: mariejosee@nevylanguage.org

TECHNICAL W EB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

- Goldentrading.co.za
- Likonzi.com
- https://lint2016.github.io/My-CV/
- Team Leads/Senior developer: Mr. Mexci Musa

Tel: 061 411 8059/0796707160

Starting date: February 2021 until now

Position: Junior developer

Duties and Responsibilities:

 Design, Development 	, Implementatior	of new features	and software solutions.
---	------------------	-----------------	-------------------------

Writing and modifying code and debugging software

Ш	Pair with other developers and learn the software development process and life cycle.
	Construct and implement application solutions.
	Construct/develop programs including coding, testing, and debugging using modern development tools/cloud services and logic apps.
	Ensure documentation of code/classes.
	Design application prototypes.
	Indicate program unit structure.
	Focus on depth of knowledge and expertise in a certain language, tool set and area of the stack
	Assist senior developer in his relative job function.